# Riley Reid

66 Denny Cr Regina, SK Canada S4N 5J9

306 596 1010 rreid112@gmail.com rjreid.ca

#### SUMMARY

A driven developer that keeps up with the current coding standards offering over 10+ years of software development experience as well as 5+ years of Android development experience working on multiple apps.

You can view my portfolio at https://rjreid.ca.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Android Developer, Trov

Regina, SK June 2019 - Current

The app I currently work on is not released to the public and I am not allowed to talk about it much. I can say that I handle everything from the app architecture to feature development and code refactors. I do all things Android and handle the normal Android developer things. I was with a team of 3 when I started at the company but I am now the sole Android developer

#### Accomplishments

- Lead the analytics efforts on Android. This included attending meetings with product people to discuss events that we would like to track
- Helped the ios team with the ios app where I could to help them catch
  up as they were behind when I joined the company
- Started committing code on my first day at the company

## Principal Android Developer, GasBuddy

Regina, SK Jan 2016 - June 2019

Work on all parts of the GasBuddy app with a small Android team that consists of 6 members. Responsible for writing clear and concise code, auditing pull requests, writing unit tests, fixing bugs, watching and responding to crash reports, and attending daily meetings.

#### Accomplishments

- Redesigned the GasBuddy app with a complete overhaul (UI and architecture) top to bottom
- Lead the teams efforts to move towards Kotlin
- Push new Beta and Production release on a weekly basis
- Always up to date on crash reports and analytics to deliver the best user experience possible
- Promoted to Team Lead which requires me to lead a team of 4 Android developers.

## Software Developer, GasBuddy

Regina, SK Jan 2013 - Jan 2016 Started by developing websites for convenience stores. Quickly transitioned to working on backend software and databases. Responsible for training new employees, writing clear and concise code, documenting new features, writing unit tests, and brainstorming ideas for new features that would be useful.

#### Accomplishments

- Completed 20 to 30 hours of work per week while attending university
- Trained new employees while I was still in university
- Designed and developed an internal dashboard to manage client websites
- Designed and developed an external dashboard for our clients to manage a lot of their own website content

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Regina

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science 2010 - 2015

Participated in the co-op program and completed four work terms that lasted four months each

## **SKILLS**

- Kotlin, Java
- Android SDK
- JSON, XML
- Retrofit, RxJava 2, Dagger 2, and many more!
- Work well as an individual as well as in a team
- Self motivator with a strong work ethic
- Keep myself organized and on task
- Working knowledge of Agile methodology

#### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request.